Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
Jascha Heifetz Collection
1911-1972
Archive of Recorded Sound
Pfeiffer, John
ARS.0046
27 box(es) 22 boxes of 10" and 12" sound discs; 5 boxes of 12" open reel tapes
The collection contains primarily sound recordings of performances of Jascha Heifetz, but it also includes recordings of other artists, some of whom were collaborators with Heifetz, as well as one recording of his teacher, Leopold Auer. There are 924 recordings on 10" and 12" sound discs, including test pressings, instantaneous discs and commercially released records. Most of the discs are 78 rpm recordings, but there are also a few 33 1/2 rpm 12" discs. In addition to audio discs, the collection contains 88 recordings on magnetic tape which consist of 1/4" tape on 10" reels. 61 of the tapes were made between December 14, 1954 and November 21, 1972. 27 of the tapes are undated. The collection also includes a computer-generated inventory of the collection prepared by the donor.
Arrangement
The recordings are arranged in three series: Series 1: 10" discs; Series 2: 12" discs; Series 3: Open Reel Tapes. Series 1 and 2 are each divided into three sub-series: (1) Instantaneous Discs; (2) Test Pressings, (3) Commercially Released Recordings. Within each sub-series the discs are arranged by manufacturer name and matrix number. The tapes are arranged chronologically by recording date with the undated recordings following the dated recordings. The undated recordings had been arranged by the donor in the order of identifying numbers on the tapes. Although it has been possible to provide dates for these undated recordings, and the date information is included with each individual tape listing in this finding aid, the original order of the tapes has been maintained.
Biographical / Historical
Jascha Heifetz, legendary American violinist, was born in Vilnius on February 2, 1901. His first teacher was his own father, but he also studied with Elias Malkin before being accepted into the St. Petersburg Conservatory in 1910. He studied first with Leopold Auer’s assistant, Nalbandyan, and then with Auer himself. Heifetz had impressed audiences from the age of six when he performed Mendelssohn’s Violin Concerto. At the age of ten he performed in St. Petersburg, and his highly successful Berlin debut took place on May 23, 1912. Later that same year he performed with the Berlin Philharmonic under the direction of Arthur Nikisch. In 1917 Heifetz was offered the opportunity to perform a concert tour of the United States, and on October 27 that year he made his Carnegie Hall debut. In 1925 Heifetz became an American citizen.
During the early 1920s Heifetz performed in England, Australia and East Asia, and later in the decade he performed in Palestine. In 1934 he made a return concert visit to Russia. After the Second World War Heifetz reduced the number of his concert appearances although he made notable appearances with the Israel Philharmonic Orchestra in 1967 and at Carnegie Hall, where he performed collaboratively three times in 1964 with several artists, including Piatigorsky. Other musicians with whom Heifetz collaborated in chamber concerts were Emanuel Feuermann, William Primrose and Artur Rubinstein. Beginning in 1962, Heifetz taught at the University of Southern California, Los Angeles and was the first faculty member to hold the Heifetz Chair in Music which was established in 1975.
Throughout his life Heifetz made numerous recordings on major labels such as Columbia, Decca and Gramophone, but the largest number of recordings he made were for the Victor/RCA Victor label. He composed music himself and also wrote numerous transcriptions for the violin. Under the alias Jim Hoyle, he wrote the hit song "When You Make Love to Me (Don't Make Believe)" which was sung by Bing Crosby. Heifetz also commissioned and performed several new concertos, of which probably the most well-known is the Violin Concerto by William Walton. Other concertos commissioned by Heifetz include those by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Erich Wolfgang Korngold, Louis Gruenberg and Arnold Schoenberg (which Heifetz never played).
The supreme artistry of Jascha Heifetz is undisputed, and his name has become synonymous with absolute perfection in violin playing. During his lifetime he owned more than one Stradivarius violin, and although his last public performance took place in 1972, he continued to play up to the end of his life. Heifetz died on December 10, 1987 in Los Angeles.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The Jascha Heifetz Collection was assembled and donated by the long-time friend and record producer of Mr. Heifetz, John (Jack) Pfeiffer, in January and July 1990.
Separated Materials
Several discs in the collection were received broken or cracked. Those discs have been removed from the sequence and placed in Box 1. Box 1 is stored at the Archive of Recorded Sound.
Violin and piano music; Violin with orchestra; Concertos (Violin); Sonatas (Violin and piano); Test pressings (Sound recordings); Violinists -- United States; Violin music; Pfeiffer, John; Heifetz, Jascha
- 10" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Instantaneous Recordings
    - Box 2: Decca/Gramophone/Odeon/Instantaneous, Instantaneous 78 rpm discs (Box 2)
      Nazarro, Cliff; Achron, Isidor; Dinicu, Grigoraș
      - New Year's Eve, 10" 78 rpm instantaneous sound disc (Box 2, Disc 1)
        Scope and Contents
        Handwritten in pencil on label on one side: New Year's Eve, Jascha's house
        Audiodisc: recorded on both sides; only one side is labeled
      - Trials, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 2)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Trials
        Presto, U.S.A.: recorded on one side only
      - Re-take of Sibelius slow movement, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 3)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Re-take of Sibelius slow movement - other [side] almost blanc
        Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 47, D minor. Adagio di molto
        Presto U.S.A.: recorded on both sides
      - Experiment at 630, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 4)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Experiment at 630 [Park?] - nothing much
      - Recorded via radio, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 5)
        Handwritten on label: Recorded via radio from [??] Air on G string played by Heifetz
        Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Suites, orchestra, BWV 1068, D major. Air; arr.
        Real Art Recording Co.: recorded on both sides
      - Dinicu, Grigoraș. Hora staccato, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 6)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Dub - speed 78 - Hora stacato, Dinicu & his orchestra
        Soundcraft: recorded on one side only
      - Padilla, José, 1889-1960. Bien amada. Valencia., 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 7)
        Title in typescript on label: Valencia
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Isidor Achron, piano
        Studio & Artists: 37 [number handwritten in pencil on label]
      - Lane, Burton, 1912-1997. I'll remember, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 8)
        Performed by Cliff Nazarro
        United Research Laboratories: Dub on one side only
      - Jascha Heifetz: Ford Hour., [May 1939?]; 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 9)
        Burleigh, Cecil, 1885-1980. Small concert pieces. Moto perpetuo
        All information in red typescript on plain white label
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz
      - Somebody else's recording, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 10)
        Handwritten in blue ink on plain white label: Somebody else's recording
        Recorded on both sides
      - Potpourri of Somebody else's recording, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 11)
        Handwritten in blue ink on plain white label: Potpourri of Somebody else's recording ('cello, voice & guitare)
      - Piano trials by. J.H., 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 12)
        Handwritten in blue ink on plain white label: Piano trials by J. H. [i.e. Jascha Heifetz]
      - Habanera**, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 13)
        Separated Materials
        Disc is broken and has been placed in Box 1
      - Levee dance, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 14)
        Handwritten in blue ink on plain white label: Levee dance - M - Jascha Heifetz
        No. stamped on label: 72444
        Recorded on one side only
      - 15, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 15)
      - 16, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 16)
      - Tempo de blue, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 17)
      - 20, 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 20)
  - Test Pressings, 78 rpm discs
    - Box 2: Decca/Gramophone/His Master's Voice
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Vocalise en forme d'habanera; arr., folders (Box 2, Disc 13)
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. It ain't necessarily so; arr., [no year given] December 17; 1 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 15)
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. Bess, you is my woman; arr., 1 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 16)
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. Selections; arr., 1 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 17)
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Preludes, piano (1926). No. 1; arr., 1946 January 21; 10" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 18)
        Handwritten on label: Preludes, pt. 1
        Decca: 73177B
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Preludes, piano (1926). No. 2; arr., 1946 January 25; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 19)
        Handwritten on label: Preludes, part 2
        Decca: 73178A1
      - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Preludes, piano (1926). No. 3, [no year given] December 17; 1 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 20)
      - Aguirre, Julián, 1868-1924. Huella., 1946 January 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 21)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Huella - Jascha Heifetz
        Decca: 73183A1
      - Bennett, Robert Russell, 1894-1981. Hexapoda. Gut-Bucket Gus -- Bennett, Robert Russell, 1894-1981. Hexapoda. Jane shakes her hair., 1946 January 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 22)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: Hexapoda I & II, Jascha Heifetz
        Decca: 73196B
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Carnaval des animaux. Cygne., 1946 January 21; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 23)
        Handwritten in blue ink on label: The swan - Jascha Heifetz
        Decca: 73207C
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Carnaval des animaux. Cygne, 1946 April 10; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 24)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Englische Suiten. Nr. 3 Gavotte, no. 1; arr. -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Englische Suiten. Nr. 3. Gavotte, no. 2; arr., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 26)
        Bach-Heifetz, Gavotte and musette [from English suite no. 3, arr. by Heifetz]
        Gramophone: OB.6041-1
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Enfant prodigue. Prélude; arr., 1934 February 24; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 27)
        Arranged for violin and piano
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; unidentified pianist
        Gramophone: OB.6055-1.[square]
      - Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Capricieuse., 1934 February 21; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 28)
        Gramophone: OB.6059-2.[square]
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 20, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 29)
        Gramophone: OB.6104-2[square]
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 13, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 30)
        Gramophone: OB.6105-2[square]
      - Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Tallahassee suite. Bygone memories -- Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Tallahassee suite. After sundown, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 31)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; E. Bay, piano
        Gramophone: DA.1567; OEA.4853-1[square], OEA.4854-1[square] (matrix)
      - Dinicu, Grigoraș. Hora staccato., 1937 April 9; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 32)
        Hora staccato / Dinicu-Heifetz
        Gramophone: OEA.4894-1[square]
    - Box 3: Victor, 78 rpm discs
      Chotzinoff, Samuel; Benoist, André; Achron, Isidor
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ruinen von Athen. Marcia alla turca., 1917 December 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 67)
        Etched into disc: Turkish march; handwritten on sleeve: Beethoven
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; André Benoist, piano
        Victor: B21074 4
      - Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Méditation., 1917 December 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 68)
        Etched into disc: Meditation; handwritten on sleeve: Glazounoff
        Victor: B21269 2 [matrix number listed incorrectly as 21260 on original inventory]
      - Moszkowski, Moritz, 1854-1925. Guitarre; arr., 1918 October 3; Disc is missing a small chip; recording area is not affected.; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 69)
        Etched into disc: Guitarre; handwritten on sleeve: Moszkowsky
        Victor: B22270 2
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Siciliano et rigaudon, violin, piano., 1918 October 3; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 70)
        Etched into disc: Sicilienne and Rigaudon; handwritten on sleeve: Francoeus
        Victor: B22271 2
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Danzas españolas, op. 23. Zapateado., 1918 October 4; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 71)
        Etched into disc: Zapateado; handwritten on sleeve: Sarasate
        Victor: B22273 1; 66097 (etched in disc)
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 20., 1918 October 4; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 72)
        Etched into disc: Caprice XX; handwritten on sleeve: Paganini
        Victor: B22274 2
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Minuet, violin, piano, D major., 1918 October 4; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 73)
        Etched into disc: Minuet; handwritten on sleeve: Porpora - Kreisler?
        Victor: B22275 2
      - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Myrthen. Widmung., 1919 October 13; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 74)
        Etched into disc: Dedication; handwritten on sleeve: Schumann
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Samuel Chotzinoff, piano
        Victor: B23403 2
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Ecole moderne. Alla saltarella., 1919 October 13; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 75)
        Etched into disc: Saltarella; handwritten on sleeve: Wieniawski (old)
        Victor: B23404 2
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Ecole moderne. Alla saltarella., 1924 December 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 76)
        Etched into disc: Caprice; handwritten on sleeve: Wieniawski Saltarella (new)
        Victor: B23404 5
      - D’Ambrosio, A. (Alfredo), 1871-1914. Serenade, violin, piano, op. 4., 1919 October 13; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 77)
        Etched into disc: Serenade; handwritten on sleeve: D’ambrosio
        Victor: B23405 1
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Souvenir d’un lieu cher. Scherzo., 1919 October 13; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 78)
        Etched into disc: Scherzo; handwritten on label: Tschaikovsky
        Victor: B23406 2
      - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Slovanské tance, op. 46. No. 2; arr., 1919 October 14; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 79)
        Etched into disc: Slavonic Dances; handwritten on sleeve: Dvorak
        Victor: B23411 2
      - Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Raĭmonda. Grand adagio., 1922 October 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 80)
        Etched into disc: Grand Adagio; handwritten on sleeve: Glazounoff
        Victor: B27033 2
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew pieces. Hebrew lullaby; arr., 1922 October 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 81)
        Etched into disc: Hebrew Lullaby; handwritten on sleeve: Achron
        Victor: B27034 1
      - Granados, Enrique, 1867-1916. Danzas españolas [unspecified]., 1922 October 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 82)
        Etched into disc: Spanish Dance; handwritten on sleeve: Granados
        Victor: B27035 1
      - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Quartets, strings, H. III, 63, D major. Vivace; arr., 1922 October 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 83)
        Etched into disc: Vivace; handwritten on sleeve: Haydn
        Victor: B27037 1
      - Boulanger, Lili, 1893-1918. Nocturne, violin, piano., 1924 September 25; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 84)
        Etched into disc: Nocturne; handwritten on sleeve: Boulanfer
        Victor: B30929 3
      - Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. [unspecified] Tambourin., 1924 September 25; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 85)
        Etched into disc: Tambourin; handwritten on sleeve: Rameau
        Victor: B30932 3
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Stimmungen, op. 32, no. 1., 1924 September 24; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 86)
        Etched into disc: Stimmung; handwritten on sleeve: Achron
        Victor: B30936 1; 312; 10; 1048A (additional numbers stamped in disc)
      - Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Gentle maiden -- Boulanger, Lili, 1893-1918. Cortège, violin, piano., 1924 December 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 87)
        Etched into disc: Gentle Maiden etc.; handwritten on sleeve: Gentle Maiden, Cortege, Scott, Boulanger
        Victor: B31379 2
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. [unspecified] Siciliana., 1924 December 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 88)
        Etched into disc: Sicilienne; handwritten on label: Bach Sicilienne
        Victor: B31381 3
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. [unspecified] Sarabande., [1917?]; 10" vinyl 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 89)
        Handwritten on white label in ink: Heifetz Sarabande Bach; handwritten on label in pencil: BS-81350-4 [17?]/10/15 [Mohn?]
        Handwritten in ink on reverse of label: 10-19-48 R E.[P.?]
        Victor: 81350 4 (stamped in disc)
      - Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d’Arlequin. Valse bluette; arr., 1928 May 8; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 90)
        Etched into disc: Valse Bluette; handwritten on sleeve: Drigo
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; [Isadore Achron?], piano
        Victor: BVE 21068 5
      - Padilla, José, 1889-1960. Bien amada. Valencia, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 91)
      - Ponce, Manuel M. (Manuel María), 1882-1948. Estrellita., 1928 May 8; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 92)
        Etched into disc: Estrellita; handwritten on sleeve: Ponce
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [Isadore Achron?], piano
        Victor: BVE 43945 4
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 13; arr., 1920 September 16; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 94)
        Handwritten on label: Caprice XIII; handwritten on sleeve: Paganini
        Victor: 670A 2; 2 U670A 3 (additional numbers stamped in disc)
      - Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Capricieuse., 1917 November 9; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 95)
        Handwritten on label: Capricieuse; handwritten on sleeve: Elgar
        Victor: A 672A 2
      - Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d’Arlequin. Valse bluette; arr., 1917 November 9; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 96)
        Handwritten on label: Valse Bluette; handwritten on sleeve: Drigo (old)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; André Benoist, piano
        Victor: W 673A 2
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Ungarische Tänze. Nr. 1., 1920 September 16; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 97)
        Handwritten on label: Hung. Dance # 1; handwritten on sleeve: Brahms
        Victor: U 675A 2
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 334, D major. Menuetto (3rd movement); arr., 1919 October 28; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 102)
        Handwritten on label in pencil: Menuet Mozart
        Victor: 997A 1
      - Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938. Impressions. Valse., 1920 September 17; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 105)
        Handwritten on label in pencil: Valse Godovsky
        Victor: 1048B 2
    - Box 4: Victor/RCA Victor, 78 rpm discs
      Benoist, André; Sandor, Arpad; Bay, Emanuel; Achron, Isidor
      - Ponce, Manuel M. (Manuel María), 1882-1948. Estrellita; arr., 1928 May 8; 1946 September 25; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 115)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: Estrellita; handwritten on reverse: 3B 9-25-46 E.G.
        RCA Victor: 1332A (handwritten on label and stamped in disc)
        Recorded May 8, 1928
      - Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d’Arlequin. Valse bluette; arr., 1928 May 8; 1946 September 25; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 116)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: Valse Bluette; handwritten on reverse: E.G. 9-25-46
        Etched into disc: BE 21068 May 8/28 Valse Bluette Heifetz
        RCA Victor: 1332B-5 (handwritten on label and stamped in disc); 21068 (stamped in disc)
      - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Songs from Shakespeare’s plays. Arise; arr. -- Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Skazka o t︠s︡are Saltane. Nu, teperʹ, moĭ shmelʹ., 1934; 1946 September 26; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 121)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: Sea murmurs - Bumble-bee; handwritten on reverse: E.G. 9-26-46
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Arpad Sandor, piano
        RCA Victor: 1645A-2 (handwritten on label and stamped in disc)
        Recorded 1934
      - Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938. Triakontameron. Alt Wien; arr., 1934; 1946 September 26; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 122)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: Alt-Wien [Old Vienna]; handwritten on reverse: E.G. 9-26-46
        RCA Victor: 1645B-2 (handwritten on label and stamped in disc)
      - Dinicu, Grigoraș. Hora staccato; arr., [193-?]; 1946 September 26; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 129)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: Hora Staccato; handwritten on reverse: E.G. 9-26-46
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Emanuel Bay, piano
        RCA Victor: 1864A-1; OEA 4894-1[square]
        Recorded in Europe [193-?]
      - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare’s Viel Lärmen um nichts. Holzapfel und Schlehwein., [193-?]; 1946 September 26; 10" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 130)
        Handwritten on label in blue ink: [illegible] Korngold; handwritten on reverse: E.G. 9-26-46
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Arpad Sander, piano
        RCA Victor: 1864B-2; OB 6054-2[square]
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ruinen von Athen. Du hast in deines Ärmels Falten; arr., 1917 November 9; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 155)
        Handwritten on disc in pencil: Chorus of dervishes; handwritten on sleeve: Beethoven Auer
        Victor: 64759-1-10 (etched on disc)
      - Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938. Triakontameron. Alt Wien., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 159)
        Handwritten on white label in black ink: Alt Wien 81353-1 New York Jascha Heifetz; handwritten on sleeve: Godowsky
        RCA Victor [logo stamped into reverse of disc]: 81353-1
  - Commercially Released Recordings, 78 rpm discs